Guide to 'Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt' - Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref173
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
'Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt' - Hisham Khatib Collection
Circa 1910-1920
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
Unknown
AD.MC.030_ref173
40
58 Photographic Prints 58 postcards and photographic prints over 20 pages of an album
Generally good, some brittle and warped.
E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173
Content Description
Digital surrogates of 58 photographs and postcards focused on Palestine, Jordan, Syria, Lebanon and and Egypt as well as a very small number from Europe. Some postcard publishers are identified, most are unknown.
Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palestine; Jordan; Egypt; Syria; Lebanon; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Postcards; Travel; Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
- The front cover of the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000001; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Syria; Lebanon; Egypt; Palestine
- The inside front cover of the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000002; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Syria; Egypt; Lebanon; Palestine
- From the top left clockwise: a postcard entitled "Chef de bedouins pasteurs" [a Bedouin chief holding a gun], a train crossing over a bridge, the Great Sphinx of Giza, and a group of boys and men in front of a tent., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000003; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Men; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Palm Trees; Guns; Weapons; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Mountains/Hills; Bridges; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Women; Children; Boys; Facial Hair; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tents; Transportation; Cigarettes; Trains; Water; Rivers; French Writing; Egypt; Deserts
- From the top clockwise: a hand-colored postcard showing Straight Street and the Bab Sharki gate in Damascus, the Al-Hamidiyah Souq, the courtyard of the Umayyad Mosque, a building on a street, and the Temple of Baalshamin at the ruins of Palmyra., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000004; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Religious Sites; Doors/Entrances; Damascus, Syria; Markets; Street Vendors; Crowds; Palmyra (Tadmur), Syria; Umayyad Mosque/Great Mosque of Damascus; Mosques; Temples
- From the top left clockwise: a landscape of Damascus, the Hejaz Railway Station, a view of Marjeh Square (Martyrs' Square), a view of a bridge with a building in the background, and a view of Marjeh Square (Martyrs' Square)., Circa 1913-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000005; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Damascus, Syria; Landscapes; Railways; Buildings; Architecture; Bridges; Mountains/Hills; Carriages/Coaches; Streets/Roads; Horses; Transportation; Electricity; Monuments/Memorials; Cars/Trucks; Crowds; Men; Women; Rivers; Desalination of water
- From the top left clockwise: (No.41) a hand-colored postcard showing mosques in Aleppo, (No.44) a hand-colored postcard showing a partial view of eastern Aleppo, (No.43) a hand-colored postcard showing a view of south-eastern Aleppo, and a postcard of the Aleppo Citadel, and details of a window at the Khan al-Saboun (Al Saboun Caravanserai)., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000006; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Mosques; Aleppo, Syria; Religious Sites; French Writing; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Architecture; Electricity; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Citadel of Aleppo
- From the top left clockwise: (No.32) a postcard of Al-Otrush Mosque, (No.13) a hand-colored postcard of Al Khosrofieh Mosque, a hand-colored postcard entitled "Beduines Syriennes" [Syrian Bedouins], and a hand-colored postcard showing a general view of Hama, Syria., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000007; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Hama Governorate, Syria; Aleppo, Syria; Bridges; Water; Mountains/Hills; Women; Regional/National Dress; Tobacco pipes; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits
- Top: a hand-colored postcard of Tripoli, Lebanon. Bottom: (No.651) a hand-colored postcard showing the Citadel of Raymond de Saint-Gilles in Tripoli [Qala'at Sanjil/Tarablus], Lebanon., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000008; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Tripoli, Lebanon; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Railways; Transportation; Palm Trees; French Writing
- From the top left clockwise: the Temple of Bacchus in Baalbek, the Temple of Jupiter in Baalbek, two men sitting on the banks of the Jordan River, and a column from the Temple of Bacchus., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000009; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Baalbek, Lebanon; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Jordan River; Rivers; Water; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils
- From the top left clockwise: a view of the Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah or Al Aqsa Mosque in Haram esh-Sharif / Temple Mount, a crowd of people at the Western Wall, a hand-colored postcard of the tablets in the Church of the Pater Noster, a crowded street in Jerusalem, and a postcard of the Damascus Gate., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000010; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Jerusalem; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Doors/Entrances; Damascus Gate, Jerusalem; Crowds; Men; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Umbrellas/Parasols; Boys; Children; Hats; Streets/Roads; Markets; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Western Wall; Church of the Pater Noster; Street Vendors; Workers; Donkeys; Group Portraits; Churches; Praying
- From the top left clockwisee: a hand-colored postcard of people praying at the Western Wall, (No.31) an interior view of Al-Aqsa Mosque, a hand-colored postcard of the interior of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre, a view of the Mount of Olives including Absalom's Tomb and Zecharias' Tomb, and a view of the Abbey of the Dormition., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000011; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; French Writing; Jerusalem; Western Wall; Praying; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Women; Religious Sites; Churches; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Landscapes; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Tomb of Absalom; Tombs/Mausoleums; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Mosques; Paintings; Chandeliers
- From the top clockwise: a hand-colored postcard of the Cenacle, a postcard of the Pool of Siloam, and a postcard of the Church of the Redeemer, Jerusalem., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000012; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Water; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
- From the top down: a view of terraced hills in Bethlehem, a general view of Acre featuring Al-Jazzar Mosque, and (No.104) a hand-colored postcard of Elish'a Spring., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000013; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Bethlehem; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Churches; Religious Sites; Mosques; Landscapes; ʻAkkā/Acre; Jerusalem; Fountains; Water; Bridges; Men; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Children; Mountains/Hills
- From the top left clockwise: a hand-colored postcard of Bethany, a hand-colored postcard of Tiberias, a hand-colored postcard of the Stella Maris Monastery in Haifa, a hand-colored postcard of a marketplace in Jaffaa, and a view of Nazareth taken from Kafr Kanna., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000014; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Landscapes; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Men; Countryside/Rural; Water; Al-Eizariya/Bethany; Tiberias/Tabariyyah; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Lakes; Tents; Nazareth; Streets/Roads; Jaffa; Markets; Street Vendors; Workers; Food; Camels; Animals; Palm Trees; Kafr Kanna, Galilee; French Writing; Religious Sites; Monasteries/Convents; Haifa
- From the top left clockwise: men and women posing on a village road, an aerial view of Cairo, people walking on a street, a view of men working with wooden mechanisms at the City of the Dead, a village in Egypt, an archaeological site with a palm forest in the background, a landscape of the Great Pyramids, a group portrait of men in front of the Sphinx and the Great Pyramids., Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000015; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Palm Trees; Mountains/Hills; Mosques; Religious Ceremony; Cameras; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Camels; Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Deserts; Boys; Children; Donkeys; Tombs/Mausoleums; Countryside/Rural; Egypt; Cairo, Egypt; Workers
- A blank page in the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000016; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Syria; Lebanon; Palestine; Egypt
- A blank page in the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000017; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
- A blank page in the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000018; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Syria; Egypt; Palestine; Lebanon
- The inside back cover of the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000019; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
- The back cover of the album "Postcards and Snapshots of Syria, Lebanon, Palestine and Egypt.", Circa 1910-1920; AD_MC_030_ref173_000020; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Electronic Records AD_MC_30_ref173)
  Palestine; Syria; Lebanon; Egypt